<resources>

    <string name="app_name">Tour Guide</string>
    <string name="name">Name</string>
    <string name="address">Address</string>
    <string name="description">Description</string>
    <string name="choose">Choose a city to get started</string>
    <string name="welcome">Welcome to Express Vladimir Region tour guide!</string>
    <string name="back">Back</string>

    <string name="nav_header">Express Vladimir region tour guide</string>
    <string name="about">About</string>
    <string name="vladimir">Vladimir</string>
    <string name="suzdal">Suzdal</string>
    <string name="murom">Murom</string>
    <string name="raduzhnyy">Raduzhnyy</string>

    <string name="golden_gates">Golden Gates</string>
    <string name="golden_gates_address">Bol\'shaya Moskovskaya str., 1A</string>
    <string name="central_park">Central Park of Vladimir\'s 850th anniversary</string>
    <string name="central_park_address">Between Baturina, Mira, Mikhailovskaya and Suzdalskaya streets</string>
    <string name="dmitrievskiy_cathedral">Dmitrievskiy Cathedral</string>
    <string name="dmitrievskiy_cathedral_address">Sobornaya ploschad\' (in the center of Vladimir)</string>
    <string name="georgievakaya_street">Georgievskaya Street</string>
    <string name="georgievakaya_street_address">(obviously) Georgievskaya Street</string>
    <string name="city_council">City Council</string>
    <string name="city_council_address">Bol\'shaya Moskovskaya str., 54</string>
    <string name="crystal_museum">Crystal Museum</string>
    <string name="crystal_museum_address">Dvoryanskaya str., 2</string>
    <string name="patriarchal_gardens">Patriarchal Gardens Park</string>
    <string name="patriarchal_gardens_address">Gor\'kogo str., d.62</string>
    <string name="alexander_nevskiy_square">Alexander Nevskiy Square</string>
    <string name="alexander_nevskiy_square_address">Bol\'shaya Moskovskaya str., 66a</string>
    <string name="observation_deck">Observation Deck</string>
    <string name="observation_deck_address">At the end of Pushkin\'s Park</string>
    <string name="spasskiy_hill">Spasskiy Hill</string>
    <string name="spasskiy_hill_address">Near Water Tower on Kozlov Val str.</string>
    <string name="old_pharmacy">Old Pharmacy</string>
    <string name="old_pharmacy_address">Georgievskaya str., 3</string>
    <string name="lunacharskiy_theatre">Lunacharskiy Drama Theatre</string>
    <string name="lunacharskiy_theatre_address">Dvoryanskaya str., 4</string>
    <string name="uspenskiy_cathedral">Uspenskiy Cathedral</string>
    <string name="uspenskiy_cathedral_address">Sobornaya square</string>
    <string name="water_tower">Water Tower</string>
    <string name="water_tower_address">from theatre square to Kozlov Val str.</string>
    <string name="ww2_memorial">World War 2 Memorial</string>
    <string name="ww2_memorial_address">Victory Square, where Lenin prospect crosses Chaikovskiy str.</string>

    <string name="eternal_fire">Eternal Fire</string>
    <string name="mead">Suzdal Mead</string>
    <string name="pokrovskiy_monastery">Pokrovskiy monastery</string>
    <string name="pozharskiy_monument">Monument to Dmitriy Pozharskiy</string>
    <string name="rizopolozhenskiy_monastery">Rizopolozhenskiy monastery</string>
    <string name="spaso_efimyev_monastery">Spaso-Efimyev monastery</string>
    <string name="suzdal_kremlin">Suzdal Kremlin</string>
    <string name="trading_area">Historical Trading Area</string>
    <string name="wooden_archtecture_museum">Wooden architecture museum</string>
    
    <string name="spaso_preobrazhenskiy_monastery">Spaso-Preobrazhenskiy monastery</string>
    <string name="spaso_preobrazhenskiy_monastery_address">Lakina str., 1-a</string>
    <string name="armored_train">\"Ilya Muromets\" armored train</string>
    <string name="armored_train_address">Vladimirskoe highway, in the park of the 50th anniversary of the Soviet authority</string>
    <string name="karacharovo">Karacharovo village</string>
    <string name="karacharovo_address">Karacharovo microdistrict</string>
    <string name="monument_to_ilya_muromets">Monument to Ilya Muromets</string>
    <string name="monument_to_ilya_muromets_address">Observation deck in Okskiy park</string>
    <string name="murom_bridge">Murom bridge</string>
    <string name="murom_bridge_address">Located at the turn from the Nizhny Novgorod highway (route P72, P125)</string>
    <string name="railway_museum">Railway station and museum</string>
    <string name="railway_museum_address">Privokzalnaya square</string>
    <string name="svyato_voznesenskiy_cathedral">Svyato-Voznesenskiy Cathedral</string>
    <string name="svyato_voznesenskiy_cathedral_address">Moskovskaya str., 15a</string>
    <string name="ww2_monument_verbovchany">World War 2 monument to Verbovchan citizens</string>
    <string name="ww2_monument_verbovchany_address">located at the intersection of Leningradskaya and 30 Let Pobedy streets</string>
    <string name="zvorykin_monument">Monument to Vladimir Zvorykin</string>
    <string name="zvorykin_monument_address">Pervomajskaya str., 4</string>
    
    <string name="chernobyl_monument">Chernobyl disaster monument</string>
    <string name="bmp">Monument to veterans of military actions</string>
    <string name="dragon">\"Skyrim\" monument</string>
    <string name="fountain">City singing fountain</string>
    <string name="kosminov_monument">Monument to city founder I.S. Kosminov</string>
    <string name="seamen_monument">Monument to the dead seamen</string>
    <string name="pentagon">\"Pentagon\" building</string>
    <string name="stella">World War 2 Stella</string>

    <string name="golden_gates_description">A road to the city is opened by the Golden Gate (1164).
        In their meaning they were like the Golden Gate of Constantinople or the Golden Gates
        of Kiev,from which the road to the heart of the capital began - to the monasteries and the
        St. Sophia Cathedral. But the Golden Gate of Vladimir was not only the triumphal arch of the
        city. It was a battle fortress that could withstand the onslaught of the Tatar hordes.
    </string>
    <string name="central_park_description">Entertainment in the park is not limited only to
        attractions. Concerts, contests, meetings with interesting people are held constantly here.
        And always holidays are celebrated by special programs. There are exhibitions of children's
        drawings, gaming, theatrical, and sports competitions, performances of creative groups.
    </string>
    <string name="dmitrieskiy_cathedral_description">the court temple, built by Vsevolod the 
        Big Nest in the prince\'s court and consecrated in honor of the Great Martyr Demetrius 
        of Thessalonica. According to N. N. Voronin, it was built in 1194-1197. 
        The cathedral is famous for its white stone carvings - its walls are decorated with about 
        600 reliefs depicting saints, mythical and real animals. Most of the reliefs were preserved 
        in their original form.
    </string>
    <string name="georgievakaya_street_description">Georgievskaya street recently became pedestrian
        with two new viewing platforms appeared at once. Georgievskaya street was landscaped by the
        day of the city of Vladimir in 2015 - the buildings were restored, the road was laid with
        paving stones, set benches, set up sculptures, and at the end of the street there was an
        observation deck with views of the Uspenskiy Cathedral.
    </string>
    <string name="city_council_description">The building of the City Duma was built in 1907 in the very center
        of the city on Cathedral Square with the money of Vladimir merchants.
        The City Duma is a 2-story building under a metal four-tiled roof.
        The central facade ends on two sides with two small tents.
        The facades are decorated with elements typical of Old Russian architecture.
        The building is decorated with a keel arch under the balcony at the level of the 2nd floor.
    </string>
    <string name="crystal_museum_description">The work of the masters of glass and crystal is represented by
        products that can only cause admiration. From colored glass and crystal there are presented 
        instruments for wine, water, honey, as well as vases, decorative dishes and other products.
    </string>
    <string name="patriarchal_gardens_description">One of the most beautiful places in Vladimir.
        The garden dates back to the 16th century. In Vladimir there was no patriarch\'s residence,
        but the cherry orchard was specially planted, where the capital\'s clergy came to rest.
        Patriarchal gardens are 3 hectares of land planted with dozens of varieties of fruit trees
        and shrubs, berries, wild plants and herbs. The garden descends to the Klyazma steps, it is
        multi-level, presented in the traditions of French park architecture.
    </string>
    <string name="alexander_nevskiy_square_description">The square located next to the city\'s
        planetarium is very small in space. In the square there is a monument to Alexander Nevsky.
        The uniqueness of this place in a stunning form opening to the Klyazmen floodplain.
        The lawns with wood framing prevail.
    </string>
    <string name="observation_deck_description">From the observation platform in Pushkin Park one
        can see the architectural monuments of Vladimir and the magnificent panorama of Vladimir\'s
        expanses, in the distance one can see the Country Park. On July 28, 2007, in connection with
        the 850th anniversary of the transfer of the capital of Rus from Kiev to Vladimir on the
        observation platform a monument to the founder of the city, Prince Vladimir Krasnoe
        Solnyshko (Red Sun) and Saint Fedor, the baptizer of the Vladimir land.
    </string>
    <string name="spasskiy_hill_description">One of the new sightseens - a small square near the
        church, called "Spasskiy Hill" was landscaped to the City Day of Vladimir in 2014.
        On the Spasskiy hill, guests are greeted by the "Oak tree".It is known that it is widespread
        in the forests of the region. From the observation platform of the Spasskiy Hill,
        one will see a beautiful view on the Uspenskiy Cathedral.
    </string>
    <string name="old_pharmacy_description">A two-storey semi-stone house under an iron roof was
        built in the late 18th century. as an outbuilding at the gubernia house. In 1805, on
        September 15, the first state pharmacy was opened in the Vladimir region on the first floor.
        Before that time, there was only a private pharmacy in the city, opened as far back as 1781.
        Until 2011, on the first floor of the house, there was a pharmacy, known to the citizens as
        "old pharmacy".
    </string>
    <string name="lunacharskiy_theatre_description">The Drama Theater in Vladimir was founded in
        1848 and is one of the oldest in the country. The repertoire of the theater includes
        performances based on the works of famous classical authors, as well as plays by
        contemporary playwrights and fairy tales for children.
    </string>
    <string name="uspenskiy_cathedral_description">An outstanding monument of white stone
        architecture of pre-Mongol Rus. Orthodox church of the Vladimir diocese; also the state
        museum. Historically, before the rise of Moscow, was the main (cathedral) temple of
        Vladimir-Suzdal Rus, the Vladimir and Moscow princes married in the great reign. A monument
        of Russian architecture of the 12th century, which served as a model for a number of later
        cathedrals, including the Uspensky Cathedral of Aristotle Fioravanti. One of the few
        churches in which the unique frescoes of Andrei Rublev are preserved.
    </string>
    <string name="water_tower_description">In the former water tower, there is a very interesting
        exposition of the Old Vladimir Museum-Reserve. Visitors will see photos of old Vladimir
        streets, household items, interiors, print production of pre-revolutionary times - all this
        recreates a vivid picture of the life and customs of the old Vladimir. On the top of the
        tower, there\'s an observation platform, where one can see the panorama of the city with its
        new districts, ancient monuments, picturesque views.
    </string>
    <string name="ww2_memorial_description">Square of military glory in Vladimir. The memorial on
        the square was built on the site of the Yamskaya Kazan zekvi demolished in 1966. The main
        component of the architectural design of the memorial on Victory Square is the stele in
        honor of the military units formed in Vladimir in 1941-1942. Contains a list of 9 military
        units formed in Vladimir in 1941-42.
    </string>

    <string name="eternal_fire_description">\"The eternal memory of the Suzdalians who died in the
        battles for the freedom and independence of our homeland\" is engraved on a memorial stone.
        Due to the specificity of Suzdal, Eternal Fire is not a necessary place to visit,
        but in the autumn and winter many tourists come to it just to warm up.
    </string>
    <string name="mead_description">It\'s not actually a sightseen, but nevertheless it\'s a unique
    drink that is produced ONLY in Suzdal by historical recipes. Mead which is called in russian
        "Medovuha" is original Russian traditional drink based on natural honey, prepared by the
        method of natural fermentation. The composition of the product is absolutely natural and
        suitable even for those who carefully choose food and drinks for the safety of ingredients.
    </string>
    <string name="pokrovskiy_monastery_description">Pokrovsky Monastery is an active women\'s
        monastery, and received its gloomy fame as a place of exile and imprisonment for
        aristocratic prisoners such as Vasiliy III\'s wife Solomoniya Saburova, wife of Ivan the
        Terrible\'s son Yevdokia, wife of Ivan the Terrible Anna Vasilchikova, wife of Peter I
        Evdokia Lopukhina.
    </string>
    <string name="pozharskiy_monument_description">The monument to Dmitry Mikhailovich Pozharsky,
        the national Russian hero, leader of the people\'s militia, which freed the country from
        Polish-Lithuanian invaders, stands against the backdrop of the entrance tower of the
        Spaso-Efimyev Monastery near the southern wall, in the square. The monument to the national
        hero was solemnly opened October 28, 1955.
    </string>
    <string name="rizopolozhenskiy_monastery_description">In 1207, at the crossroads, Bishop Ioann
        of Rostov-Suzdal founded the convent of Reese of the Theotokos or Rizopolozhensky. The
        history of this monastery is closely connected with the famous Suzdal saint, whose relics
        many people still go to worship - the Monk Euphrosyne of Suzdal.
    </string>
    <string name="spaso_efimyev_monastery_description">this landmark of Suzdal could well be put on
        the first place in the conditional ranking. In front of the main entrance, located in the
        monastery tower, is a small square with a monument to the most famous Suzdal citizen -
        Prince Dmitry Pozharsky. Spaso-Efimiev monastery was originally conceived as a fortress,
        the Suzdal principality after its unification with Nizhny Novgorod and the transfer of the
        squad to Nizhny needed a strong outpost to protect the western borders.
    </string>
    <string name="suzdal_kremlin_description">In the 12th century, the city began to be built on the
        site where the museum under the name "Suzdal Kremlin" is located nowadays. Here, in the bend
        of Kamenka river, the first earthworks were erected and the first city cathedral was built.
        The Kremlin preserved the ramparts, moats and some churches that historically belonged
        to the Kremlin. Now Suzdal Kremlin is a museum with numerous expositions dedicated to the
        history of Suzdal land, famous people associated with it, treasures from monasteries and
        churches, ancient Russian painting and applied art.
    </string>
    <string name="trading_area_description">The shopping area is the central square of Suzdal.
        It originated in the middle of the 12th century and has since retained its layout, which in
        modern urban planning can be called a unique fact. Here, in the center of public life, all
        the large-scale holidays and events of the city are held. It is a popular tourist
        destination due to the large number of churches located here, and of course the guest house.
        Initially, all the churches were wooden, but in the 18th century after the fire they were
        replaced by stone ones, and in the 19th century the restoration of the courtyard building
        was carried out, where more than a hundred shopping malls were once located.
    </string>
    <string name="wooden_archtecture_museum_description">The Museum of Wooden Architecture and
        Peasant Life is a complex of architectural monuments in the open air. The exposition of the
        museum reproduces a small village with cottages, churches, household buildings and windmills
        of the XVII-XIX centuries, which were brought here from different parts of the Vladimir
        region. Over the reconstructed village towering two churches, erected without a single nail.
        Here you can see the house of a simple farm laborer, a well-to-do peasant and a merchant.
        In the interiors the huts store samovars and furniture, dishes and toys, wooden spinning
        wheels and looms.
    </string>

    <string name="chernobyl_monument_description"> Pedestal with a memorial plate in memory of the
        participants in the liquidation of the Chernobyl nuclear power plant accident was installed
        In April 2001 near the house number 2 in the first block.
    </string>
    <string name="bmp_description">This is a monument to veterans of Afghanistan and Chechnya war
        conflicts. It was installed in 2015.</string>
    <string name="dragon_description">It\'s not an official sightseen. Actually it\'s a private
    monument of local oil company. It can be figured out by cautious inspection of the image - the
        dragon is nestling an oil tower. Raduzhnyy citizens call this monument a "Skyrim dragon" in
        parallel with respective computer game.
    </string>
    <string name="fountain_description">Main city fountain, which works every evening during
        snowless period of the year. It has musical and lumiere accompanying. This in one of the
        favourite places for citizens to spend their evening time.
    </string>
    <string name="kosminov_monument_description">The name of the founder of Raduzhnyy is known to
        every inhabitant of the city. It is General Ivan Sergeevich Kosminov. In 1971, when the
        construction of the Raduga design bureau was started, Kosminov was commissioned to supervise
        the work. Simultaneously, the construction of necessary housing facilities and
        infrastructure was carried out. So it was first formed the village of Vladimir-30,
        and then the city of Raduzhnyy.</string>
    <string name="seamen_monument_description">This monument was installed at July 30, 2004 in the
        honor of seamen, who died defending the glory of russian fleet.</string>
    <string name="pentagon_description">This is an unfinished building of a modern living house.
        Hardly anybody now will tell why it is called \"Pentagon\". It\'s not an official sightseen,
        and its area is restricted to enter. But this object is not guarded by anyone, and Raduzhnyy
        citizens, especially younger ones very love this building, because if one climbs on the
        roof, then a very beautiful view on town and long distances is opened.
    </string>
    <string name="stella_description">This high stone stele was erected in memory of those were
        killed during the World War 2. Established in honor of the 70th anniversary of victory.
    </string>

    <string name="spaso_preobrazhenskiy_monastery_description">one of the oldest monasteries in the
        north-east of Russia. Belongs to the Vladimir-Suzdal Diocese of the Russian Orthodox Church.
        This monastery is one of the main attractions of Murom, which guests visit. Presumably the
        relics of Elijah the Murom of the saint are in the Chievo-Pechora Lavra. Bogatyr was
        canonized among her other companions in 1643. Information about his life is drawn from
        folk legends - in the annals we do not meet his name, but in the Western European sagas
        of the XII-XIII centuries a certain Ilya from Russia is mentioned.
    </string>
    <string name="armored_train_description">During the Great Patriotic War, Murom was a rear city.
        Its inhabitants selflessly worked in factories, raised funds for the defense of the country.
        So, as a gift to the front, workers of the locomotive repair shops built an armored train
        in 1941-1942. The authorities wanted to call him "For the Motherland", but the builders at
        the rally defended their name - "Ilya Muromets". It is symbolic that during the war the
        Murom iron hero destroyed in battle the enemy armored train "Adolf Hitler".
    </string>
    <string name="karacharovo_description">Picturesque micro district Karacharovo (once the
        village-home of Ilya of Murom) - in itself is already a tourist attraction. According to
        written sources, the village of Karacharovo is known since the XVII century. From the
        monuments of architecture here is the estate "Krasnaya Gora" including a manor house,
        two outbuildings, outbuildings and a linden alley. The village has preserved the sights
        associated with the name of the most famous of its native - the hero Ilya of Murom.
    </string>
    <string name="monument_to_ilya_muromets_description">On the observation deck in 1999, a monument
        to the hero Ilya Muromets was erected. Sculptor Vyacheslav Klykov (his most famous work is
        a monument to Marshal G.K. Zhukov in Moscow) depicted him in two hypostases - as a warrior
        and as a monk: in a raised hand the saint holds a sword, and in another - a cross.
        The militant gesture of Ilya Muromets is not accidental - here, on the banks of the Oka
        River, the border of the Russian lands passed in antiquity. At the pedestal of the monument
        are the figures of seated griffins. With his left paw, fabulous birds rest on a shield.
    </string>
    <string name="murom_bridge_description">Cable-stayed bridge across the Oka River near the city
        of Murom in the Vladimir region and the city of Navashino in the Nizhny Novgorod region.
        Recently it was recognized as the most beautiful bridge in Russia, and according to the
        deputy head of the Federal Road Agency is a world-class landmark that the whole country
        can be proud of rightfully.
    </string>
    <string name="railway_museum_description">The railway station building was, remains and, for
        certain, will remain the pride of the Murom, one of the business cards and attractions of
        the city. To the 100th anniversary of the opening, a small museum was opened inside the
        building, where exhibits from different eras tell of the history of the Murom railway station.
    </string>
    <string name="svyato_voznesenskiy_cathedral_description">One of the most beautiful temples in
        Murom, located at the intersection of two important city highways of the streets of Moscow
        and Leo Tolstoy. It was built in 1729 instead of the wooden Ascension church.
    </string>
    <string name="ww2_monument_verbovchany_description">Monument to the people who fell in battle
        for their homeland in 1941-1945. was installed in the town of Murom in the town of Murom in
        1975. The history of the monument is interesting. According to the project manager G.N.
        Karachev in the famous film "Optimistic tragedy" he saw a monument to the sailors of the
        Civil War. Out of a single block of stone, the figures of the dead seamen were appearing.
        The concept of sculpture shocked G.N. Karachev and he had an idea about creating a similar
        monument in the village of Verbovsk, but dedicated to the perished of the Verbovians during
        the Great Patriotic War.
    </string>
    <string name="zvorykin_monument_description">Vladimir Zvorykin is the most famous Muromlian
        (after Ilya Muromets), the founder of modern television. He was born in Murom in the family
        of the merchant of the first guild of Kozma Zvorykin. The idea of composition of the
        monument: a student of the St. Petersburg "polytechnic" of the early 20th century,
        Vladimir Zvorykin, sitting on a bench near his home.
    </string>

</resources>
